<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<books>

  <!--AzkuvalianRecital-->

  <book ID="Azkuvalian_Lyrics" Title="{{azkuvalian|Azkuvalian}} Scripture">
    <page>
    Akatylian verse:
    Children of lesser soul.
    Witness forth the flame of light!
    Let forth the light of fate.
    See as it burns the light!
    Upon the fire of sin.
    Upon the flame of heresy!
    Witness forth.
    Eternal light!
    </page>
    <page>
    Techpriest verse:
    May the flame bear witness.
    Upon the flame's return!
    Sanctity falls as light sees flame.
    May the gods bear witness!
    To the flame of heresy's fall.
    That Arkane sees his fate!
    As it will be forever known.
    Arekena of the metalic flame!
    </page>
    <page>
    Thatylian verse:
    The metal shines.
    With fiery light!
    As sin burns upon the flame.
    Beckon forth!
    The light of fire.
    As it sings with eternal life!
    May the gods bear witness.
    For their fate is forever known!
    </page>
    <page>
    Xyatylian verse:
    Heresy's flame upon damnation's curse.
    Sanctity falls upon the flame's return!
    Mortality's disgrace, axitari swine.
    Gods forsaken, do they not understand?
    A single damned thing of their forsaken fate?
    May the gods see to it!
    For it shall be ensured.
    The light of fire, beckons a new flame!
    </page>
  </book>

  <book ID="AzkuvalianSermon" Title="AzkuvalianSermon">
    <page>Children of lesser soul.</page>
    <page>Witness forth the flame of light!</page>
    <page>Let forth the light of fate.</page>
    <page>See as it burns the light!</page>
    <page>Upon the fire of sin.</page>
    <page>Upon the flame of heresy!</page>
    <page>Witness forth.</page>
    <page>Eternal light!</page>
    <page>May the flame bear witness.</page>
    <page>Upon the flame's return!</page>
    <page>Sanctity falls as light sees flame.</page>
    <page>May the gods bear witness!</page>
    <page>To the flame of heresy's fall.</page>
    <page>That Arkane sees his fate!</page>
    <page>As it will be forever known.</page>
    <page>Arekena of the metalic flame!</page>
    <page>The metal shines.</page>
    <page>With fiery light!</page>
    <page>As sin burns upon the flame.</page>
    <page>Beckon forth!</page>
    <page>The light of fire.</page>
    <page>As it sings with eternal life!</page>
    <page>May the gods bear witness.</page>
    <page>For their fate is forever known!</page>
    <page>Heresy's flame upon damnation's curse.</page>
    <page>Sanctity falls upon the flame's return!</page>
    <page>Mortality's disgrace, axitari swine.</page>
    <page>Gods forsaken, do they not understand?</page>
    <page>A single damned thing of their forsaken fate?</page>
    <page>May the gods see to it!</page>
    <page>For it shall be ensured.</page>
    <page>The light of fire, beckons a new flame!</page>
  </book>

  <!--Books-->

  <book ID="AkzatoDiary" Title="torn diary" Format="Auto" Margins="1,2,2,2">
    <page>
    Chyrasyl, 13, 270ae.
    Arrived at the grand library on Azkuvalia.
    Found a book, with some particular glyphs.
    </page>
    <page>
    {{emote|*The page is filled with glyphs written in a pattern you can't decipher*}}
    </page>
    <page>
    Chyrasyl, 20, 270ae.
    Child of lesser soul.
    Such a degrading thing to be refered to as.
    </page>
    <page>
    Chyrasyl, 24, 270ae.
    Who are the gods, the Azkuvalian refer to?
    Is it those of the Syrenalians? The one Daemina betrothed, namesake of my place of birth?
    Or is it tied to their metalic constructs?
    </page>
    <page>
    Chyrasyl, 28, 270ae.
    Why are the Akatylians so, calm?
    Why are the Thatylians so, direct?
    Why are the Xyatylians so, harsh?
    </page>
    <page>
    Chavyr, 2, 270ae.
    I was approached by one of the techpriests today.
    I told him to fuck himself, after he began flirting with me.
    </page>
    <page>
    Chavyr, 3, 270ae.
    That techpriest came to where I was staying along with his chosen,
    and lets just say: my blade handled the issue.
    </page>
    <page>
    Chavyr, 14, 270ae.
    I saw Arekena, Azkedara talking to a group of acolytes.
    They didn't seem to be fond of Arekane, Arkane's rise to power.
    I'll try to speak with her tommorow.
    </page>
    <page>
    Chavyr, 15, 270ae.
    I spoke with Arekena, Azkedara about what I overheard.
    In part it seemed as though she'd almost berate me,
    however, it seems I have some business to handle.
    </page>
    <page>
    Chavyr, 31, 270ae.
    Given recent events:
    Arekena, Azkedara has offered to house me under her care,
    in part whilst she handle's Arekane, Arkane's fanatics.
    </page>
    <page>
    Chara, 3, 270ae.
    Arikal, my arkaedus half brother.
    Such a delightful individual, as much as he's a jackass.
    </page>
    <page>
    Chara, 3, 270ae.
    The scholars are holding a fast, this coming week.
    Hopefully their request for me to partake doesn't lead to anything.
    </page>
    <page>
    Chara, 13, 270ae.
    Arekena, Azkedara came to me the other night, and we made out.
    Today, she came and handed me her cerimonial archcannon,
    before she left on some journey alongside her rogues.
    </page>
    <page>
    Chara, 29, 270ae.
    Arikal showed up with his usual attitude the other night,
    and I lost control of myself.
    I'm starting to question why I was fasting in the first damn place.
    </page>
    <page>
    Chara, 30, 270ae.
    Arikal's alright, all things considered of course.
    The reformation process Daemina had taught me is done,
    and his egg is back at his place, hopefully he understands.
    </page>
    <page>
    Chara, 31, 270ae.
    Arikal relatively expectedly came to visit again.
    There was some select words spoken.
    </page>
    <page>
    {{emote|*There's a distinct claw mark where half the page remained*}}

Why did I bother attending their sermons,
what reasoning was there, for my presence?
    </page>
    <page>
    Akcha, 2, 300ae.
Due to certain events: I as well most of those I'm close to are now residing on Syrenalia.
This fucking artificial planet.
    </page>
    <page>
    Akcha, 4, 300ae.
Arikal has us staying in the company of a queen.
Whom he's been trying to seduce, for some fucking idiotic reason.
    </page>
    <page>
    Akcha, 6, 300ae.
Eilyndara's her name, and she came to me with a glass of her piss.
Relevant thing of note: syrenalian urine coagulates when fertilized.
In relation: Syrenalian biology has no physical difference ; they're equally capable regardless.
So not as different from me and my body, with the exception of them being incapable of self-fertilisation.
    </page>
    <page>
    Akcha, 7, 300ae.
Since I brought it up on the previous page:
On my 100th hatchday: I was dreaming, and there was a full set of 3 eggs.
Suizva had woken me up, and had a friend of hers whom was a gutchirper, or in other words: a voderaskidaly medical assistant.
After he diagnosed the caused: he whispered to Suizva which filled her with joy.
Akailios, whom was tending to them: after they had hatched, brought me flowers congratulating me for what were vaguely biological clones of myself.
    </page>
    <page>
    Akcha, 8, 300ae.
    As much as I appreciate drinking this fruit flavoured piss.
    I think she's flirting with me, because of Arikal's stubborness.
    </page>
    <page>
    Akcha, 10, 300ae.
    Trivial that was the reason, and Arikal's pissed as usual.
    </page>
    <page>
    Akcha, 15, 300ae.
    I went to see Fiera Talfiera sing at a local bar or whatever they want to call it.
    She walked up to me afterwards, and I'm currently staying at her place.
    </page>
    <page>
    Akcha, 16, 300ae.
    Syrenalian akordox, and their physical distinctions to their non-half mortal equivalents.
    We went out and spent a bit of time together, and as much as I appreciate the design of syrenalian clothing, dresses included.
    Her combed tail is lovely.
    </page>
    <page>
    Einfernax, 19, 300ae.
    {{emote|*There's a well-drawn sketch of a fiery heart with a depiction of a arinate inside.*}}
    Mutually anxious, rough but lovely.
    </page>
    <page>
    Akcha, 20, 300ae.
    Lovely bitch, stole my diary.
    Speaking of which: this safeguarding thing, seems to have a lot of similaries to the reformation/rebirth process.
    Except being more of a cautionary measure, in the random case.
    </page>
    <page>
    Akcha, 21, 300ae.
    Stole her dress, she seems to be enjoying seeing me walk around in it.
    </page>
    <page>
    Einfernax, 22, 300ae.
    Invited Twylia over, and gods the look of Akzato's face was cute.
    She seemed hesitant to speak with her, given their mother's mutual ties.
    Akcha, 22, 300ae.
    It was something to meet the daughter of the former high queen of Octusaria.
    I get they come from a penumbral moon where a number of things are vampiric, though why the edged tongue?
    </page>
    <page>
    Einfernax, 25, 300ae.
    Made a special drink for Akzato, hopefully a little tarazila venom isn't too much.
    Akcha, 25, 300ae.
    Your piss burnt my mouth, also next time: half the amount of venom you poured into it, 2.5 is still lethal and 1.5 can impact the circulatory system.
    I'm going to guess the stun spears the illiatari have, aren't for public use?
    </page>
    <page>
    Akcha, 30, 300ae.
    Fiera combed my mane during a bath, simply said: it felt nice.
    </page>
    <page>
    Einferix, 1, 300ae.
    Was in bed with Akzato this morning, and she was fast asleep cuddled up to me with her arms wrapped tightly around.
    I began to pet her, and gods how her purring vibrated through my chest.
    She woke up briefly to lovingly bite my neck before falling back to sleep.
    Even a bit of a meow here and there, in between the chirps.
    Isn't there a saying relating to a voderai's meow?
    Eichal, 1, 300ae.
    "If you hear a voderai bark, then approach with ease. If you hear a voderai chirp, then calmly approach. If you hear a voderai meow, then approach cautiously." - Akfiasaki
    My elder half-blood sister's father.
    </page>
    <page>
    Eichal, 2, 300ae.
    Some jackass unleashed 8 pairs of leiskwings into the city.
    These fucking wyverns are meant to be one of Dorator's "apex predators", and a single shot from Azkesalityr, immediatly downs one of them.
    The local vexara, wasn't that fond of seeing Arekena, Azkedara's archcannon, though she seemed to appreciate the help.
    </page>
    <page>
    Eichal, 3, 300ae.
    Fiera came into the bedroom the other night holding Suizva in her arms.
    Suizva needed a motherly sister's comfort, and mentioned Akailios was busy comforting Akafiol.
    </page>
    <page>
    Eichal, 4, 300ae.
    So Akafiol and a high councillor are dating.
    Am I supposed to be surprised that Savistato is letting his spouse date Akafiol?
    </page>
    <page>
    Eichal, 5, 300ae.
    Savistato arrived, and Akafiol's alright.
    The illiatari was here a few hours, but at least he got them to leave.
    </page>
    <page>
    Eichal, 10, 300ae.
    Fiera got ahold of Varinesa, and we're now on her whatever the hell it's called.
    There's no reasoning for this thing to have as many fucking weapons as it does.
    Her and Arikal have been fighting, for the past few days.
    Arikal dated her a fair bit, whilst he was volunteering.
    </page>
    <page>
    Eichal, 11, 300ae.
    Waking up in the middle of the night to hear Arikal getting his ass kicked, is always a lovely thing.
    He came into the room with scorched feathers, and it almost looked like he was smiling.
    </page>
    <page>
    Eichal, 14, 300ae.
    Varinesa invited me to her room the other night, and had me chose between a selection of her clothes.
    I'm still wearing them, and Hellshot said I look hot in them.
    I don't care much for mercenaries though, regardless of affiliation.
    </page>
    <page>
    ?, ?, ?ae.
    We've arrived somewhere, I have no idea where and I could care less.
    Varinesa gave me some equipment, and Arikal's already waiting outside.
    </page>
  </book>

  <book ID="AlvaneiaUFS" Title="{{einfieran|Upon the Flame's Sun}}">
    <page>
    A flame kindled from the depths of Hell.
    An angel of fire bursts forth upon the world.
    An eye blazing with hellish flame.
    For the Hand of Kata, fires his hellish shot.
    </page>
    <page>
    The alluring light burns with passionate flame.
    A song echoes the flame that burns within the heart.
    A fiery heart that beckons the love of those around.
    For even a mere spark can set a world alight.
    </page>
  </book>

  <!--Stories-->

  <book ID="Azkesalityr" Title="{{azkuvalian|Azkesalityr}}">
    <page>
    Forged by the techpriests of the primordial moon, echoes a sounding shot.
    For hence upon the Arekena of the Xyatylian hierarchy, bends the fabric of metalic light.
    Beckoning a new flame, she called upon fate's sin to blast the cindering light to damnation.
    </page>
    <page>
    Since the times of her rule, Arekena Azkedara recants her title.
    She raised her cannon high, gifting it to a beloved member of her flock of rogues.
    For henceforth, she takes aim against the heresy of her Akatylian brother.
    </page>
  </book>

  <book ID="Kaliskato" Title="{{dasdarfoxan|Kaliskato}}">
    <page>
    Latched with time, bound by many.
    Catch the find, lost to many.
    Hatch the kind, seen to many.
    </page>
    <page>
    Once gifted to a Kalavylian high seer, Kaliskato was weilded with passion.
    In spite of the seer's benign dishonesty, the axe remained truthful.
    For the seer had kept her caravan safe, and protected their peaceful travels until their untimely end by an Akdaran warband.
    </page>
  </book>

  <book ID="Valykaityr" Title="{{eiltaresian|Valykaityr}}">
    <page>
    Thine frozen shard of Eiltaresian glass, forms upon a wide point and narrowly edged within permafrost.
    Thine frozen shaft imbued by crystaline mana.
    Thine frozen spirit, once of thee Valykaityr, sworn velyte born and breed as thine queen's protector.
    </page>
    <page>
    Rise upon thee Korshek, for thy valour and wisdom.
    Stand before thine sisters, and bring grace unto thee glacial wastes.
    Stand upon thee frozen bastions, as thine spear lunges forth as thine queen's shield.
    </page>
  </book>

  <book ID="Zanivira" Title="{{eilsavian|Zanivira}}">
    <page>
    Metal cases the guilded barrel.
    Metal flares from the guilded stock.
    Metal sings from the rotary chambers.
    </page>
    <page>
    This rifle was commissioned by a Ceran Laxieran trademaster.
    It has sung countless shells, as fire sang from it's chambers.
    It has all but weathered from usage, as it was polished with care.
    </page>
  </book>

</books>